export const quizQuestions_9 = {
  questions: [
    {
      question: 'In React, what is a side effect?',
      choices: ['Changes to state within a component', 'Operations like data fetching, subscriptions, or manually changing the DOM', 'Any function that returns a value', 'A feature of Redux'],
      correctAnswer: 'Operations like data fetching, subscriptions, or manually changing the DOM',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the use of the "children" prop in React?',
      choices: ['To pass data to child components', 'To define the children of a component in JSX', 'To manage the internal state of a component', 'To control the rendering of child components'],
      correctAnswer: 'To define the children of a component in JSX',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what does "immutability" mean in the context of component state?',
      choices: ['State cannot be changed', 'State should not be changed directly, but via setState()', 'State is always mutable', 'State is a read-only property'],
      correctAnswer: 'State should not be changed directly, but via setState()',
    },
    {
      question: 'How can React performance be optimized when working with lists?',
      choices: ['By always using the PureComponent', 'By avoiding the use of keys', 'By using the "key" prop effectively', 'By rendering all list items at once'],
      correctAnswer: 'By using the "key" prop effectively',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the purpose of "PropTypes" in React?',
      choices: ['To specify the types of props a component can receive', 'To define default values for props', 'To generate prop-related documentation', 'To make all props optional'],
      correctAnswer: 'To specify the types of props a component can receive',
    },
    {
      question: 'Which of the following is NOT a valid way to define a component in React?',
      choices: ['Function component', 'Class component', 'Hook component', 'Stateless functional component'],
      correctAnswer: 'Hook component',
    },
    {
      question: 'What is the React Virtual DOM?',
      choices: ['A more efficient version of the regular DOM', 'A copy of the main DOM that React keeps in memory', 'A feature that allows React to manipulate CSS', 'A tool for managing state in applications'],
      correctAnswer: 'A copy of the main DOM that React keeps in memory',
    },
    {
      question: 'What does the "useRef" hook return in React?',
      choices: ['A function', 'A component instance', 'A mutable ref object', 'The current state value'],
      correctAnswer: 'A mutable ref object',
    },
    {
      question: 'How does "React.memo" contribute to a component\'s performance?',
      choices: ['It memorizes the state of the component', 'It prevents re-rendering if props or state haven’t changed', 'It reduces the component\'s memory usage', 'It automatically splits the component into smaller chunks'],
      correctAnswer: 'It prevents re-rendering if props or state haven’t changed',
    },
    {
      question: 'In React, what is the role of reducers in the "useReducer" hook?',
      choices: ['To break down the component into smaller parts', 'To manage global state', 'To specify how the state changes in response to actions', 'To combine multiple states into one'],
      correctAnswer: 'To specify how the state changes in response to actions',
    }
  ]
};
